Hello English learners. Welcome back to
English Pod, my name is Marco and I'm Erica.
And today we have an elementary lesson
for you and we are at the supermarket.
That's right we're at the
grocery store and we're
going to learn some
language you can use when
you want to pay for your
groceries. So this lesson
was requested by one
of our users that wanted
vocabulary and different
phrases that are used in
the supermarket when
the person is about to pay
for all the things they
need. The trait and we
also have some great
language that the person
who is actually selling
the the groceries can use.
All right so let's listen to a dialogue
for the first time and see what happens.
Excuse me sir. This is
the express check out
name for people who
have 15 items or fewer.
It looks like you have more than 15
items there. Oh come on. I have 16 items.
Cut me some slack will
ya? Fine. Please place your
items on the belt and push
your shopping card through.
Do you prefer paper or plastic? Plastic.
I also have a couple of coupons.
No problem I'll take those.
Sir these coupons expired yesterday.
Darn! Oh well I guess it's just not my day.
Thanks anyway.
Do you have a club card or will it be cash?
Yeah I got a club card. Here you go.
Will this be debit or credit?
Debit please. Also could I get cash back?
$50 would be great. Yeah sure.
Your total is $78.33.
Here's your seat have a nice day.
How are you?
Well we can see in this
dialogue that the guy
was able to buy his food
and you know they were
using some really
interesting helpful language.
That's right and so
why don't we look at this
language now in
language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay we have six
words for you today and the first one.
The girl the cashier says this
is the express checkout lane.
Alright so check out
lane. The checkout lane.
So the checkout lane is
the place where you get in
line to pay for all the
goods you bought.
Right so the checkout lane. No why
did she say express checkout lane?
So in grocery stores
or in supermarkets
sometimes you have a specific
checkout lane that's faster.
Okay because people
have less things.
So express is the faster
checkout lane. Right
the faster one. Alright
so next she tells the
guy to put your items
on the belt. Okay the belt.
The belt. A belt. Now
we know belt as the thing
you put around your
waist to keep your pants up.
Right but in a supermarket
the belt is the moving
table that you put your
groceries on so the cash
ier starts to pass them
through. Okay so the belt.
Okay the belt. Put your
groceries on the belt
and then the guy said that
he had a couple of coupons.
Coupons. Coupons.
Okay so what is a coupon?
A coupon is a piece of paper
you can use to get a discount.
Alright so it has
a discount on it.
A discount for one thing
like so maybe you buy some
some apples and you get
10% off one kind of apple.
Very good coupons. Now he presented these
coupons and she said they were expired.
The coupons expired yesterday. Expired.
To expire. Alright so to expire that means
to be older than the date
when you can use them.
Right so why don't we
listen to some other examples
of how we can use expired so we can
understand a little bit better. Example one.
I'm sorry sir. This credit card expired
five years ago. You can't use it anymore.
Example two. My driver's license expires
in a month so I have to get it renewed.
Example three. Don't drink that.
The milk has expired.
Okay so we can see his
coupons expired so they
were too old and he
couldn't use them anymore.
Exactly and now finally she asked him if
he wants to pay with his club card or cash.
So club card. Club
card. What's a club card?
So in some supermarkets
you can receive a special
type of credit card
that you can only use
for grocery shopping
and only in that store.
Right so that is a club
card. Alright so a club card.
Okay so he's going
to pay with a card but
he also asked for some
cash back. Cash back.
Could I get cash back?
Cash back. Now what what's
he talking about?
Can he get cash back?
He's paying with a card.
What does he want to do?
Well what happens is
sometimes suppose your
groceries cost $20. Okay
so instead of charging
$20 to your credit card
or your club card you
say okay put $70 so then
the cashier can give you
$50 back so you can
have cash in your pocket.
Ah so instead of going to
the ATM you can get your
money in one spot. Exactly.
Alright so that's cash back.
Interesting. Well
why don't we hear this
one more time in the
dialogue but let's slow
it down a little so we
can understand better.
Excuse me sir this is
the express checkout
lane for people that
have 15 items or fewer.
It looks like you have
more than 15 items there.
Oh come on I have 16 items.
Cut me some slack will you?
Fine please place your
items on the belt and
push your shopping cart
through. Do you prefer
paper or plastic? Plastic. I
also have a couple of coupons.
No problem I'll
take those. Sir these
coupons expired yesterday.
Darn! Oh well I guess
it's just not my day thanks anyway. Do
you have a club card or will it be cash?
Yeah I got a club card. Here
you go. Will this be debit or
credit? Debit please.
Also can I get cash back?
$50 would be great. Yeah sure.
Your total is $78 and 33 cents.
Here is your receipt.
Have a nice day. Thank you.
Alright so now that
we've listened to the
dialogue for the second
time it's time for us to
take a look at some
phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay we
have three phrases for you now.
Well the guy was not having
a very good day was he?
So he couldn't go in the express checkout
lane and he says cut me some slack.
Cut me some slack. To
cut someone some slack.
Alright now this is
an interesting and very
informal phrase so before
we explain it why don't we
listen to a couple
of other examples.
Example one. Cut me some
slack. I'm only two minutes late.
Example two. My wife just
had a baby and I'm so tired.
Got me some slack.
I'll send you the report
tomorrow. Example three.
Emily had a really bad week.
I think you should
cut her some slack.
Okay I think I can
understand it means relax
the rules a little bit. Right
so don't be so strict on me.
Yeah don't be so hard.
Now I know this phrase actually
comes from mountain climbing.
Oh oh because of the
rope. Yeah so it's like
saying the slack is loose
rope. So he's just saying
give me a little
bit more freedom.
Give me more freedom. Oh that's
interesting. Yep to cut somebody some slack.
Well now the cashier
asks him a question.
She says do you
prefer paper or plastic?
Do you prefer paper or plastic? Paper or
plastic? Now this is the common cliche of
phrase that any grocery
store cashier will use right?
Yeah so paper or
plastic what? Bags.
Paper plastic bags. Alright
so you'll hear this all the time
in every grocery store. Do
you want paper or plastic?
Right so you can choose
plastic bags or paper bags.
Okay remember this
one because when you
get it right you'll
sound really native like.
Very good and our last
phrase since he wasn't really
having a good day he
said it's just not my day.
It's just not my
day. It's not my day.
Okay so when it's not your day.
It means the day has been hard
you've not really lucky. Yeah
it's not it's not a good day for you.
Not a good day.
Alright so let's listen
to the dialogue for the
last time and then we'll
come back and talk a little bit
about grocery stores in America.
Excuse me sir. This is
the express check out
lane for people who
have 15 items or fewer.
It looks like you have
more than 15 items there.
Oh come on I have 16 items.
Cut me some slack will ya?
Fine. Please place your items on the
belt and push your shopping cart through.
Do you prefer paper
or plastic? Plastic.
I also have a couple of coupons.
No problem I'll take those.
Sir these coupons expired yesterday.
Darn! Oh well I guess it's just not my day.
Thanks anyway. Do you have
a club card or will it be cash?
Yeah I got a club
card. Here you go.
Will this be debit or
credit? Debit please.
Also could I get cash back?
$50 would be great. Yeah sure.
Your total is $78 and 33 cents.
Here's your seed have a nice day.
Well one interesting
thing I know about grocery
stores in America is that the people who
are the cashiers are very often students.
Right it's a very popular
summer job or part-time job like
college students. Yeah
or even in my hometown it
was the most common
job for high school students.
After school if you
went to the grocery store
between four o'clock and
nine o'clock at night every
single cashier would
be a high school student.
And the interesting thing
is that the cashiers are
usually women right?
Yeah always the high school
girls who are the cashiers.
And so the high school
boys would be working
in the back maybe in the
warehouse carrying boxes
or stocking the shelves.
So putting the cans on
the shelves right? Exactly.
It's a very popular
part-time job for students
in the United States
but also coupons are very
popular in America. Yeah what
is it? What is it about coupons?
Well usually for example in the Sunday
newspaper you will receive a lot of coupons.
Okay you go to the
grocery store and you have
all these coupons for like cookies or
promotion on some type of soda or drink.
So it's very popular people go
grocery shopping and then present
all these coupons and
actually you can end up
saving a good amount of
money. I know the coupons
are usually like save
two cents or save 25 cents
but I guess if you put
all of those together
you can't save money.
It's interesting because
people actually will buy
that product just because
they have a coupon. Coupons
and high school check out girls.
Well guys thanks for
listening to this show.
Now remember if
you have any questions
about the language we
were talking about in the
show please visit our
website at englishpod.com.
Right leave all your
questions and comments there
and also if you have any
other suggestions or any
doubts please let us
know and well we'll see you
guys there. So thanks for
listening and until next time. Bye!